Tanvi Sachdeva

Frontend/ .NET Full Stack Lead

Contact

Address

Pune, India, 411057

Phone

916 858 8710

E-mail

sachdevatanvi2311@gmail.c

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sachdevatanvi2311/

WWW

https://tanvisachdeva.githu b.io/tanviprofile.html

Certifications

2021-05

AZ-900 Microsoft Certified
Azure Fundamentals

2021-06

AZ-104 Microsoft Certified Azure Administrator

Skills

Javascript

React

Angular

Typescript

8+ years of experience in leading and managing project delivery with significant experience as an individual contributor.

Tech stack - React, Javascript, Typescript, Angular, .NET, C#, REST WEBAPI, HTML, CSS, Agile and Cloud, Azure certified, OOPS. More than willing to upskill in newer technologies should the project require. Have experience of working on client side in France.

Work History

2022-04 -Current

Application Development Associate Manager

Accenture - International healthcare client

- React 18, Google cloud, Redux, SCSS, Balsamiq,
 Typescript, React bootstrap, ReactJS, Swagger, GIT,
 Adobe XD, Scrum, Http, Agile
- Experience in end-to-end design, coding, testing, and deployment phases. Good knowledge of various design patterns.
- Confident in working independently or in a team in a deadline driven environment with quality deliverables.
- Strong communication and organizational skills with an ability to thrive in a fast-paced production deadline-driven environment both internal and client facing.
- Ability to solve complex development problems and produce the highest quality code while striving to push the technical boundaries of online applications
- Ability to work quickly while maintaining strong attention to detail and accuracy while adhering to W3C and accessibility guidelines.
- Strong attention to detail and understanding of UI concepts to provide perspective on front and backend technologies and their overall impact on the creative process.

2019-06 -2022-04

Technical Lead Full Stack

Sopra Steria India - European aerospace client

 Client - European multinational aerospace leader (Have international experience of working in France on client side) **REST WEBAPI**

.NET Full Stack

Scrum

Agile

C#

Leadership and Management

Azure

Project Management

HTML

CSS

Mongodb

Cloud

Programming

Object-Oriented programming

Algorithms

- Angular, React, Javascript, Typescript, .NET REST Webapi, C#, Agile, GIT, IIS, Mongodb
- Lead and performed end to end delivery of web applications starting from requirement understanding to implementation to deployment.
 Contribute to the end-to-end codebase of an application including rich frontend, thoughtful web APIs, and well-designed databases.
- Create responsive web applications using Angular and backend in .NET REST WEB API.
- Participate in all scrum ceremonies. Involved in scoping and estimation of user stories during PI planning, with Product owners/client/business.
- Mentored Web Application development team members who are on a technical career path and are interested in becoming future technical leads and engineers.

2018-06 -2019-06

Full Stack Lead Engineer

HCL Technologies Ltd. - International software client

- Client American multinational technology leader
- ASP.net MVC, GIT, Azure, jQuery, Ajax, JavaScript, CSS
- Investigating bugs in software application based on technical expertise and developing solutions in accordance with quality accredited standards.
- Mentored team members on technical front so that quality code is delivered with minimal postproduction bugs/issues.
- Effectively manage scope and client expectations on individual assignments.
- Work with an Agile team to deliver applications iteratively, and incorporate feedback into future iterations.

2015-08 -2018-04

Full Stack Developer

EdgeVerve Systems Ltd. - International telecom client

- Client American multinational telecom leader
- .NET MVC, SQL, Jquery, Javascript, Angular
- Analyze business problems, develop technology solutions to those problems and manage project through its lifecycle.

- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.
- Providing timely deliverables to client, solving post production bugs/issues were handled.

2014-09 -2015-07

Full Stack Developer

Infosys Ltd. - International telecom client

- Client American multinational telecom leader
- Full stack developer
- C#, .NET, Angular JS, SQL

Education

2010-08 -2014-07

Bachelor of Technology: Computer Science And Engineering

Rajasthan Technical University 80%

Honors and Awards

- Sopra Steria India Limited, Pinnacle Award, Feb 2021
- Sopra Steria India Limited, Pinnacle Award, June 2020
- HCL Live Wire Award, July 2018